JeremyDuval

Manager



Contact

Cell: 607-621-8376

Email: jeremydvl493@gmail.com

Address

3741 Struble Rd Endwell, NY 13760

Skills

Managing Staff Organize, schedule and manage work flow

Inventory Control
Write and interpret reports,
cost/labor projections and analysis,
inventory analysis

Communicate with customers and vendors

Source new materials, products and vendors

Proficient in most office programs,
Microsoft Access and Excel certified
Proficient in Quick Books Enterprise
Adobe Illustrator Proficient
SQL and VBA Programming
Create and execute functional
databases/programs
IT Experience

Education

MIT Professional Certificate in Coding Full Stack with MERN

2022 - 2023

MIT

Bachelors of Science, Business Management and Economics Summa Cum Laude

2017 - 2022

Suny Empire State College

Associates, Liberal Arts and Sciences 2000-2004

Suny Broome Community College

Summary

Experienced Production and IT manager with over 15 years of experience in all facets of the business environment. Has strong strong organizational and leadership skills. Tasked frequently with taking on and completing complex projects. A passion for automating tasks. Created several systems resulting in a reduction in labor costs and increased efficiency.

Experience

Mity Forms Inc.

2009 - 2022 IT, Prepress, Logistics and Production Manager ${\bf Full\textsc{-}Time}$

Manage workflow for business. Actively involved in recruiting, hiring and review processes for employees. Oversee prepress, IT and shipping. Keep track of P&L, waste, and efficiency. Source vendors and resources for new and existing products. Track inventory and purchase all assembly items for production as well as all factory supplies.

Mity Forms Inc.

2006 - 2009 Prepress & Packing and Shipping Department Supervisor Full-Time

Oversaw production in Prepress, Packing and Shipping Area. My main priority was keeping production on track to stay within on time delivery standards. I also kept purchase order and job ticket data up to date.

Mity Forms Inc.

2004 - 2006 Prepress Operator

Full-Time

Created job instructions for printing business forms and tags. Operated and maintained prepress equipment and software.

Accomplishments

 Created Purchase Order Tracking Program to enter and track purchase orders

2006 - 2022

Created modern database to enter and keep track of company purchase orders replacing the antiquated excel and paper system that was originally put in place. Also developed and integrated automated labeling system for shipping.

Press Production Database

2007 - 2022

Created program to enter production sheets in order to track production and efficiency of operators. Also provided a report to adjust COGS by category.

Sourced New Label Product Line

2012

Sourced new line of printed labels adding \$300k per year to gross sales.

Negotiated Purchase of New Digital Equipment

2016 - 2022

Sourced, negotiated and oversaw the install of new digital printing equipment reducing labor by over 30% on 3 presses.

Streamlined Product

2018

Suggested and created layout for punch die to streamline a drilled product. Result was more than a \$4000 per year labor savings.

Box Redesign

2019

Worked with box vendor on reusable tab tote for products saving thousands of dollars a year in box and tape costs.

Automated numbering files

2017 - 2022

Created program for operators to enter numbering specifications into form and automatically generate a csv data file with the click of a button for use with variable print orders.